<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Crisscross</title><description>Musings on what I do, what I make, and where I go.
I take nothing for granted and try to give everything its due space for reflection. 

</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.6</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 14:54:29 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>If I have to say hello to strangers, this is what I'd say.</title><description>&lt;p&gt;"They" told me I should market myself with a brand, so I guess this blog is me attempting that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't think a lengthy introduction is necessary, but I feel like have to write something of the sort. You'll all get to know me pretty well as I write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/if-i-have-to-say-hello-to-strangers-this-is-what-id-say/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">4753a919-8359-47a8-b595-cea2bb69e700</guid><dc:creator>Vanessa Ogbuehi</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 11:51:58 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;"They" told me I should market myself with a brand, so I guess this blog is me attempting that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't think a lengthy introduction is necessary, but I feel like have to write something of the sort. You'll all get to know me pretty well as I write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start, my name is Vanessa, but if you want to call me Nessa or something, I'd accept that too. I've never had a nickname.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to call myself a "creative professional". I'm aware of how cheesy that sounds, and I know that title lacks some legitimacy, but as this point of my career, it's the most flexible and it's appropriately descriptive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I make &lt;strong&gt;things&lt;/strong&gt;. I'm a professional costumer, theatre artist, and now web developer. Really, I'm kind of a junky when it comes to art. I'll pick up any medium as long as it serves my purposes. I still haven't found that &lt;em&gt;one thing&lt;/em&gt; that makes me go "yes, this is my life's purpose", but I'm still young, and perhaps one of the aforementioned crafts will stick longer than the others. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless, I have a unique background, and that helps in everything I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hmm. What else about me is pertinent?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm a vegan. I like controversy. I think MS Publisher is of the devil.  I think Philadelphia is the best city in the world, but the suburbs of Yokohama, Japan are pretty nice  too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's nice to meet you.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>